this is nick with logos by nick.com and
这是尼克和Nick.com的徽标
in this tutorial i'll be demonstrating
在本教程中，我将演示
how you can add some simple shading to
如何将一些简单的阴影添加到
your vector illustrations
你的矢量插图
using inkscape this is a nice little
使用Inkscape，这是一个不错的小工具
touch you can add to your designs to
你可以添加到你的设计中的触觉
make them pop a little more
让他们更流行一点
and if you don't have an example design
如果你没有一个范例设计
to try this out with then i'll have a
试一试，那我就来一杯
download link in the description of the
说明中的下载链接
video
视频
if you want to practice on this example
如果你想在这个例子上练习
design that i'm using here
我在这里使用的设计
but before we get started if you'd like
但在我们开始之前，如果你愿意
to learn more about inkscape be sure to
要了解有关Inkscape的更多信息，请务必
check out my inkscape master class
查看我的Inkscape大师课
it's a collection of over 60 videos
这是60多个视频的集合
where i go over all of the tools and
在那里我检查了所有的工具和
features in inkscape
Inkscape中的功能
and i explain what they are and
我解释了它们是什么，
demonstrate how they work i'll have a
演示它们是如何工作的，我会有一个
link in the description
描述中的链接
of the video if you want to check that
如果您想要查看视频
out so getting started here on escape as
所以在这里开始逃亡就像
you can see i have the software open the
你可以看到我把软件打开了
first thing we want to do is just make
我们要做的第一件事就是让
sure we have our snapping enabled
当然，我们已经启用了快照
up here the top icon in the very top
在这里，最上面的图标在最上面
left that says
左边说的是
enable snapping make sure that's turned
启用捕捉确保已打开该选项
on we want to come over here to where it
我们想要到这里来
says
说
snap to custom nodes make sure that's
捕捉到自定义节点确保
enabled and then snap to
已启用，然后捕捉到
smooth nodes as well and what i'm going
平滑的结点以及我要做的
to do now is i'm going to import this
现在要做的是我要导入这个
example design i have it downloaded here
示例设计我在这里下载了它
in this folder
在此文件夹中
i'm just going to click and drag this
我只需要点击并拖动这个
onto the canvas like that i'm going to
像这样画在画布上，我要
click ok to leave the default settings
单击确定以保留默认设置
as they are
就像他们一样
and there's this example shark design
这是一个鲨鱼设计的例子
that i'm going to be working with
我将和他一起工作
now let me come up here to where it says
现在让我到上面写着的地方来
view make sure you have custom selected
查看确保您已自定义选择
go to zoom zoom in at one to one
转到放大以一比一放大
and now i'm just going to hold ctrl and
现在我只需要按住Ctrl键并
shift with the select tool here hold
按住此处的选择工具按住Shift键
ctrl and shift and grab one of these
Ctrl+Shift并抓取其中一个
arrows
箭
and scale this down now for this
为了这件事，现在缩小规模
tutorial you don't have to necessarily
教程你不一定要
follow this step
请按照以下步骤操作
what i'm going to do is i'm just going
我要做的就是我要
to right click this and go to duplicate
要右键单击此选项，请转到复制
and i'm going to apply this to a
我将把这个应用到一个
duplicate copy over here
复印件在这里
i'm going to leave this one over here
我要把这个放在这里
the original so that i can show you the
原件，这样我就可以向你展示
difference
差异
between the finished design and how it
在完成的设计和它是如何
was previously just to show you how well
以前只是想向你展示一下
it makes the design look
它让设计看起来
so i have this design over here what i
所以我把这个设计放在这里，我
want to do now is just
现在要做的就是
ungroup this i'm going to come up here
把这个拆开，我要到这里来
to where it says ungroup ungroup
到它说要解组解组的位置
selected objects click on that
所选对象单击该选项
you may want to click on that just a few
您可能只想点击几个
times just to make sure that there's not
只是为了确保不会有
several layers of groupings there and
那里有几层分组，
now we can click off and deselect
现在，我们可以关闭并取消选择
everything what i'm looking at here
我在这里看到的一切
is i'm just going to imagine a light
我要想象的是一道光
source being over here on the canvas
资料来源在画布上
right here
就在这里
shining light going this way so like on
闪耀的光芒就这样照耀着你
this side of the design
设计的这一面
the right side will be like a glow or
右侧将像一道辉光或
like a highlight effect
就像高光效果
and over here will be a shading or a
而这里将是一个阴影或一个
shadow effect
阴影效果
so let me zoom in on this by holding
所以让我通过按住它来放大这个
ctrl and rolling up the mouse wheel
按住Ctrl键并滚动鼠标滚轮
and if you want to move the page around
如果您想要在页面周围移动
at any point you can just press down the
在任何时候，您只需按下
mouse wheel and move the mouse
鼠标滚轮并移动鼠标
what i'm going to do is i'm just going
我要做的就是我要
to manually draw a shaded a shaded area
手动绘制着色区域的步骤
right here i'm going to grab the bezier
就在这里，我要拿起贝塞尔
pen which is right here with the
这支笔就在这里，和
snapping enabled as it is there i'm just
快照已启用，因为它在那里，我只是
going to snap to this cusp node right
向右捕捉到这个尖点节点
there
那里
click and then come down here and click
点击，然后下来这里，点击
down here into this blue area
进入这片蓝色的区域
and then i'm going to bring the line
然后我要把这条线
going through this blue area here
穿过这片蓝色的区域
back to the starting point oops
回到起点，哎呀
back to the starting point like that
就这样回到起点
make sure you're going through the dark
确保你是在穿越黑暗
blue area the whole time
一直都是蓝色区域
and now i want to open up the fill and
现在我想打开填充物和
stroke menu which is over here fill in
填写此处的笔划菜单
stroke
卒中
or you can press ctrl shift and f on the
或者，您可以按Ctrl Shift和
keyboard and for the fill color
键盘和填充颜色
i want to make this the same shade of
我想把这件衣服做成同样的色调
blue that this light shade of blue is
蓝色，这个浅蓝色是
here only
只在这里
slightly darker so to do this i'm
稍微黑一点，所以为了做这个，我是
actually going to use the dropper tool
实际上要使用滴管工具
first i'm going to come over here to
首先我要到这里来
where it says pick colors from an image
上面写着从图像中挑选颜色
or you could press d
或者您也可以按d键
on the keyboard and just go ahead and
在键盘上，继续往前走
grab a sample selection
抓取样本选择
from that there and where it says fill
从那里和它上面写着填充的地方
in the fill tab
在填充选项卡中
i'm looking for hsl and in the l
我在找和睦家和L
row i'm going to take this and bring
我要拿着这个，带上
this to the left a little bit just to
这个稍微向左一点，就是为了
make that a little darker
把它弄得更暗一点
and i'm actually going to change the
实际上，我要更改
shade of that blue a little bit i'm
有那么一点蓝色的阴影，我是
going to take this
我要拿着这个
i'm going to take this atro and just
我要把这个ATRO和
slide this though right a little bit
把这个往右滑一点
just to make that pop out a little more
只是为了让它更突出一点
and i want to get rid of that black
我想摆脱那件黑色的衣服
outline so i'm going to hold shift and
轮廓，所以我要按住Shift键
click this red x in the bottom left
点击左下角的红色x
corner
拐角
and now what i want to do is grab the
现在我想要做的是抓住
select tool and i want to lower this
选择工具，我想降低这个
beneath these blue objects so i'm going
在这些蓝色物体下面，所以我要去
to come up here to where it says
来到这里，上面写着
lower selection one step click that once
向下选择一步单击一次
again
再来一次
again and again until it goes beneath
一次又一次，直到它沉入海底
these objects over here
这些东西在这里
now instead of using this button what i
现在不是使用这个按钮，而是我
like to do is use the keyboard shortcut
喜欢做的就是使用键盘快捷键
which is
这就是
page down so i'm just going to press
翻到下一页，所以我要按
page down until it goes beneath
向下翻页，直到翻到下面
everything like that
诸如此类的事情
or maybe not that far okay perfect right
或者也许不会太远，好的，很好
there once you've done that
一旦你做到了这一点
just take your your edit pads by nodes
只需按节点获取您的编辑板
tool and take this line and just
工具，然后走这条线，然后
manually click and drag it in
手动单击并将其拖入
so that it follows a similar contour to
所以它的轮廓类似于
this blue this dark blue line right here
这条蓝色这条深蓝色的线就在这里
and if you go to the select one you zoom
如果你去选择一个你要缩放的
back out you'll notice you've we've
退一步，你会注意到你有我们
added a little bit of shading right
向右添加了一点阴影
there
那里
now i'm going to take this and make this
现在我要拿着这个做这个
a little lighter i don't want it quite
稍微轻一点，我不太想要
that dark that looks a little better
那个看起来更好一点的深色
and i'm going to go through and do the
我要做完这件事
another shape
另一个形状
by the fin right here let me grab the
就在这里的鳍上，让我抓住
line right here
就在这里排队
then over here and then through the blue
然后在这里，然后穿过蓝色
areas the dark blue out
深蓝色区域消失
the dark blue areas until it's back to
深蓝色区域，直到它回到
the starting point like that
像这样的起点
fill it in with this shade right here so
用这个色调填满它，就这样
in
在……里面
get rid of the black outline by shift
用Shift键去除黑色轮廓
clicking the x
单击x
back to the select tool and again i'm
回到选择工具，我又一次
using page down until it goes beneath
使用PAGE DOWN直到它进入下方
those dark blue areas and now i'm going
那些深蓝色的区域，现在我要去
to grab the edit paths by
通过以下方式抓取编辑路径
these lines over here
这些线在这里
and that right there is what i'm looking
这就是我正在寻找的东西
for let me zoom out a little bit that's
让我把镜头缩小一点，这是
so now i'm going to draw another one
所以现在我要画另一幅
use the keyboard shortcuts now and work
现在使用键盘快捷键即可工作
a little bit faster so i'm going to grab
快一点，所以我要抓起
the bezier pen
贝塞尔钢笔
again over here b on the keyboard to
在键盘上再次点击这里的b键
grab that i'm going to start right here
抓住这个，我要从这里开始
at this corner
在这个拐角处
bring the line up here like that and
像这样把线拉到这里，然后
the dark blue area
深蓝色区域
back to the starting point press d on
回到起始点，按下d键
make that the same color get rid of the
把它改成同样的颜色，去掉
outline by shift-clicking the red x
按住Shift键并单击红色x
and now i'm going to grab the edit paths
现在我要获取编辑路径
n on the keyboard and i'll just take
键盘上的N，我就拿着
this and drag this in
再把这个拖进去
select tool and lower this down i'm
选择工具，然后放下这个，我是
going to press page down on the keyboard
要按键盘上的PAGE DOWN
a few times there we go
有几次我们去了那里
and now i can go back to the nodes tool
现在，我可以返回到节点工具
and i can click on this node right here
我可以点击这里的这个节点
and then i can get these little handles
然后我就可以拿到这些小把手
that'll make it easier for me to adjust
这会让我更容易适应
so i want to adjust these handles so
所以我想把这些手柄调整一下
that this shadow is following the
这个影子正跟随着
contour
等高线
of the shoulder here or the dark blue
这里的肩膀还是深蓝色的
border
边境线
that's looking pretty good right there
那里看起来很不错
as you can see
如你所见
i'm gonna do the same thing down here
我也会在这里做同样的事
only i'm gonna make this shadow
只是我要让这个影子
follow this this side right here so let
沿着这一边走，就在这里，让我们
me grab the bezier pen again
我又拿起贝塞尔钢笔
same steps as before i'm going to end
和之前一样的步骤，我要结束了
this one right about here i'm not going
这个就在这里，我不会去的
to take this all the way to the end
把这一切一直带到最后
right here i'll put it right about here
就在这里，我会把它放在这里
back through the starting point through
通过起点返回到
the dark blue areas
深蓝色区域
there we go make it the same color get
我们去把它做成同样的颜色
rid of the outline lower it down
去掉轮廓，把它往下放
with page down and then back to the
向下翻页，然后返回到
nodes tool
节点工具
and we can adjust this further and make
我们可以进一步调整，让
it fit
很合身
make it a little more fluid now you may
让它更具流动性，现在你可以
want to temporarily
想暂时
disable snapping while you're doing this
执行此操作时禁用捕捉
to do that you can just come up here
要做到这一点，你可以到这里来
and click on that because there's
然后点击它，因为有
sometimes you're going to want to adjust
有时你会想要调整
these handles
这些手柄
and the snapping gets in the way so you
抓拍挡住了你的去路
can temporarily turn that off if you
可以暂时关闭它，如果您
want to adjust these handles
我想调整这些手柄
like i'm doing here and then if you want
就像我在这里做的那样，如果你想
to turn it back on you could just press
要重新打开它，只需按下
you can just click this button or what i
你可以点击这个按钮或者我要做的事情
like to do is use the keyboard shortcut
喜欢做的就是使用键盘快捷键
which is
这就是
shift and five and there we go now it's
Shift和5，现在我们开始了
enabled again
再次启用
so looking at this illustration here
请看这里的插图
we're going to want to apply
我们会想要申请
this shadow effect maybe
这种阴影效果可能
maybe over here where the thumb is and
也许在拇指所在的地方
then after that
然后在那之后
we'll have the shadows applied to the
我们会将阴影应用到
left side of the design
设计的左侧
and then we're going to work on adding
然后我们将致力于添加
highlights to the right side of the
在屏幕右侧突出显示
design so let me just go through and
设计，所以让我先说一遍
finish up the shadows really quick
很快地把阴影处理好
okay so i've gone through and i've added
好的，我已经检查过了，我添加了
some shadows to the left side of the
左侧的一些阴影
design now i'm going to add some
设计现在我要添加一些
highlights to the right side of the
在屏幕右侧突出显示
design and i'm going to start up here
设计，我将从这里开始
with the shark's head up here because as
把鲨鱼的头放在这里，因为
we're imagining this light source is
我们想象这个光源是
coming over here from the right and
从右边走过来，然后
shining this way so
这样闪耀着光芒
let me grab the bezier pen again let me
让我再次拿起贝塞尔钢笔让我
turn snapping back on and i want to snap
重新打开捕捉，我想要捕捉
to this corner
到这个角落
i'm going to create the shot the
我要创建一个快照
highlight right here going along the top
在此突出显示，沿着顶部
of the head here
在这里的头部
snap it back to the starting point over
将其弹回起点
here
这里
bring it through the border the dark
带着它穿过黑暗的边界
blue border
蓝色边框
whoops didn't mean to do that
哎呀，我不是故意的
and back to the starting point
回到起点
and for this one i'm going to use a
对于这个，我将使用一个
lighter shade instead of a darker shade
浅色调而不是深色
so let me grab the dropper
所以让我拿起滴管
make this the same shade of blue only
只做同样深浅的蓝色
i'm going to make this one a little
我要把这个做得有点
lighter
打火机
like that let's get rid of the outline
就这样，让我们去掉大纲吧
or the stroke go back to the select tool
或者笔划返回到选择工具
page down a few times to lower it
翻几页把它放低一点
beneath the eye
在眼睛下面
and beneath the dark blue area now we
在深蓝色区域下，我们现在
can grab the edit pads by nodes tool
可抓取按结点编辑焊盘工具
i'm going to turn off snapping for this
我将为此关闭快照
part because i know for a fact that it's
部分是因为我知道这是一个事实
going to get in the way
将会成为障碍
take this node down here adjust this
把这个节点拿下来，调整这个
that's looking pretty good i just want
看起来很不错，我只是想
to get this out of the way of the eye
为了把这个从眼睛的路上移开
right here so i'm going to double click
就在这里，所以我要双击
i'm actually going to double click right
实际上，我要双击右侧
here to add a new node
此处添加新节点
and then just bring that up like that
然后就像这样提出来
that didn't come out
这件事没有出来
quite as well as i'd like so let me undo
不管我怎么想，还是让我解开吧
that to undo i'm just going to hit ctrl
要取消该操作，我只需按Ctrl键
z a couple of times
Z了几次
and let me raise this back to the top i
让我把这件事提回到最上面来
want to add this node right here
要在此处添加此节点
there we go and now i can go ahead and
我们开始了，现在我可以继续前进了
lower this down
把这个放下来
that's what i'm looking for right there
这就是我要找的东西
that's looking pretty good so i'm going
看起来很不错，所以我要走了
to add another highlight going right
向右添加另一个高光的步骤
here
这里
now since this area is white i'm just
现在，由于这个地区是白色的，我只是
going to use a more vibrant shade of
我要用一种更有活力的阴影
light blue for this highlight although
此突出显示为淡蓝色，尽管
it's technically
严格来说，这是
technically if this were like gray you
从技术上讲，如果这是灰色的你
would use white right here but since
会在这里使用白色，但因为
this is already white i'm just going to
这已经是白色的了，我只是要
like a more vibrant blue like this so
像这样更有活力的蓝色，所以
let me grab the bezier pen again
让我再拿一支贝塞尔钢笔
i'm going to start over here i'm
我要从这里开始，我是
turn snapping back i'm going to start at
转回来，我要从这里开始
this corner
这个角落
and i'll come through here like this
我会像这样穿过这里
connected to that point
连接到那个点
here
这里
and i want to make this probably the
我想让这场比赛成为
same shade of this maybe a little
和这个一样的颜色，可能有一点
lighter so let me grab the dropper
打火机，让我拿一下滴管
there we go get rid of the outline let's
好了，去掉提纲，让我们
lower this down
把这个放下来
there we go grab the nodes tool and then
在这里，我们抓住结点工具，然后
just make this follow the contour of
只要让它符合以下轮廓
that
那
i actually got to lower that down some
我真的要把它放低一点
more that's still sticking out
更多的是仍然突出的
there we go and i want to make that a
我们开始了，我想让它成为
for a little too dark for it to be a
对它来说太暗了一点不可能是
highlight like that that looks pretty
像这样突出，看起来很漂亮
so now i'm going to create another one
所以现在我要创建另一个
me grab the bezier pen
我拿起贝塞尔钢笔
right through there and then right
就在那里，然后右转
through here like this
像这样穿过这里
back to the starting point make this the
回到起点，让这成为
same color with the dropper tool
与吸管工具颜色相同
get rid of the stroke and then lower it
摆脱划水动作，然后放低它
down
降下来
like that and as you can see it's it's
就像这样，正如你所见，这是
really coming to life here so what i'm
真正在这里生活，所以我是什么
going to do is i'm going to add a few
我要做的就是添加几个
more highlights through here
更多亮点请点击此处
maybe right here on the right side of
也许就在这里的右边
the shoulder and then over here at the
肩部，然后在这里
top of the knuckles over here and maybe
在这里的指节顶端，也许
right there as well i'll have to see how
就在那里，我得看看怎么
it looks so let me go through and do
看起来是这样的，让我过去做一下
that real quick
真的很快
the areas of the design here and whether
这里的设计领域以及是否
or not this is actually correct like
或者这实际上是正确的，就像
this is
这是
how the light would actually interact
光实际上如何相互作用
with the subject like this
主题是这样的
i don't know probably not but it still
我不知道，可能不是，但它仍然
looks good enough for it to be effective
看起来足够好了，可以奏效
and to make the design pop a little more
为了让设计更流行一点
let me zoom back out here
让我放大这里
to show you what i mean i'm going to
向你展示我的意思，我要
take this original design and i'm going
拿着这个原创的设计，我就去
to put it right next to it
把它放在它旁边
and as you can see there is a clear
正如你所看到的，有一个明确的
difference there this design just seems
不同的是，这个设计看起来
more alive it seems to pop a little more
它看起来更有活力，更有活力
it just looks like a
它只是看起来像一个
like a higher quality illustration just
就像一个更高质量的插图
with some simple
用一些简单的
shading and highlights drawn with the
底纹和高光使用
bezier pen like that
像这样的贝塞尔钢笔
so that is how you can go about adding
这就是您可以进行添加的方法
some highlights and shadows and
一些高光和阴影以及
shading features to your simple
将要素着色到您的简单
illustrations using inkscape
使用Inkscape的插图
if you have any questions let me know
如果你有任何问题，请告诉我
and as always thanks for watching
一如既往地感谢您的收看
before i end the video i'd just like to
在我结束视频之前，我只想
let you know that you can watch all
让你知道你可以观看所有
future tutorials without ads
不含广告的未来教程
and before i upload them to youtube at
在我将它们上传到YouTube之前
logosbynic.com
Logosbynic.com
just click the red bell at the bottom of
只需点击底部的红色铃声
the page to get notifications and every
用于获取通知的页面和每个
time a new tutorial is posted
发布新教程的时间
you'll get to watch it before it gets
你会在它到来之前看完的
uploaded to youtube and without any
已上传到YouTube，但没有任何
advertisements
广告
if you have any questions leave a
如果您有任何问题，请在
comment below and as always thanks for
在下面发表评论，并一如既往地感谢
watching
观看
you
你